Ah, the Heckler & Koch G- 36.
啊哈，H&K公司的 G- 36突击枪
Quite deadly in the right hands.
在合适的人手里非常致命
Ah, Agent One.
啊，一号特工
I have been so looking forward to this moment.
我一直期待这一刻
Well, in that case, I'll try not to disappoint.
这样啊，我尽量不让你失望
You overestimate your power over women, Mr English.
你高估了你自己的力量，你比女人强不了多少，英格力先生
I'd say that would be virtually impossible.
我得说，那实际上不可能
Sir?Sir?
长官？长官？
Sir! Have you got them?
长官，找到了吗？
- Hmm? - The mission documents. Agent One's flying tonight.
- 嗯？ - 任务档案，一号特工今晚要出发
Yes, the mission documents. They're here somewhere. Ah, here we are.
是的，任务档案应该在这里 找到了
Agent One.
一号特工
Gentlemen.
先生们
I'm here for my documents.
我是来拿档案的
Bough, Agent One's documents, please.
大宝，一号特工的档案请拿给他
Thank you.
谢谢
Your mission documents, Agent One.
您的任务档案，一号特工
Including the codes for the submarine hatch, which I've checked myself.
包括潜水艇舱门的密码，我已经亲自试过了
Thank you.
谢谢
So, is it just France tonight,
那么，今夜就只到法国
or will you be slipping over the Pyrenees as well?
还是要一直穿过比利牛斯山？
If I told you that, I'm afraid I'd have to kill you.
如果我告诉你，就不得不杀你灭口了
Oh.
哦
Oh, yes, yes. Well, I expect you would.
哦，好的，好的，我希望你能够
Cheerio, Agent One.
加油啊，一号特工
Bonne chance. Arrivederci.
祝你好运，再见
Such class. Such distinction.
真经典，真与众不同
(所有军情七处注意了 紧急情况)
(一号特工在比亚丽兹执行任务时遇害)
(潜水艇舱门没能打开)
The greatest secret agent England's ever had snuffed out in an instant.
英国有史以来最伟大的特工转眼间就毙命了
Terrible.
太可怕了
Do you know what makes us envied the world over, Bough?
你知道为什么全世界都嫉妒我们吗，大宝？
- That there's always another agent waiting to step in. - Absolutely, sir.
- 我们总是有后备特工随时接替 - 绝对正确，长官
And every last one of them is gathered around that grave.
他们现在都聚集在墓地周围
It is our honour andprivilege to guard them while they grieve.
在他们如此悲痛的时候，保护他们是我们莫大的荣幸
Their lives are in our hands, Bough.
他们的性命就掌握在我们手里了，大宝
Everything in order, English?
一切正常吗，英格力？
I think you'll find it's rather more than just in order, sir.
长官，你会发现一切比正常还正常
You're now entering the most secure location in the whole of England.
你现在进入的是全英国最安全的地方
Pegasus, we face a national crisis.
柏伽索斯，我们正面临一场国家危机
Agent One was clearly onto something,
很明显一号特工发现了一些线索
and we have to find out what.
我们必须找出来是什么
I need another agent on this. Who else is there?
我需要再派一名特工，现在还有谁？
No one, Prime Minister. They all died in the explosion.
一个都没了，首相，他们在爆炸中都遇害了
All of them?
全部？
Well, luckily there is one who survived.
呃，幸运的是，还有一名幸存者
Who?
谁？
《憨豆特工》
（王牌间谍指南）
（潘格斯）
Right.
是的
Johnny English. I'm here to see Pegasus.
强尼·英格力 我是来见柏伽索斯的
Still, no sense rushing things.
别着急
There are some items you need to sign before your briefing.
见面前，你还得签收一些东西
This is your new retinal I.D. card,
这是你新的视网膜身份识别卡
and this is your level nine security clearance.
这是你的第九级通行证
Sign and date, please.
请签上名字和日期
Ah.
啊
Oh, reminds me of the old service issue ballpoint.
哦，让我想起了老式的耐用圆珠笔
I remember every agent would carry a pen that looked just like this.
我记得每个特工都会带一只这样的笔
Completely innocent to the untrained eye, but click it twice...
没经过训练的人一点也看不出异样，但按两下这里…
Ah, English, there you are.
啊，英格力，你来了
Have you seen my secretary?
见到我的秘书了吗？
Um... she went out.
嗯，她出去了
Um... shall we?
嗯，我们是不是该…？
Now, Agent One believed that there was a plot to steal the Crown Jewels.
一号特工相信有人阴谋盗取王室珠宝
They've recently been through a multimillion- pound restoration,
刚刚有人赞助了几百万英镑
Iargely paid for by a corporate sponsor.
对他们进行了修复
They're d ue to be unveiled toni ght at the T ower of London.
今晚将在伦敦塔展示给世人
The queen is insisting that the ceremony goes ahead, so what we want you to...
女王坚持按计划举行典礼，所以我们要你…
Hah! Who- Who...
哈！ 谁… 谁…
Who is the sponsor, sir?
谁是赞助人？
Pascal Sauvage.
派斯卡·苏瓦吉
What, that flouncy Frenchman who owns a couple of prisons?
什么，那个装模作样的拥有几间监狱的法国佬？
Sauvage's ￡7 billion empire, English,
苏瓦吉拥有70亿英镑的帝国，英格力
operates over 400 prisons in 60 countries.
在60个国家开了400多间监狱
- He's built 25 of them here. - Right, sir.
- 他在这里建了25间 - 是的，长官
The man's related to the royal family, for goodness'sake.
天哪，他还和王室有关系
As far as the prime minister's concerned,
依照首相的看法而言
he's one of the greatest friends England's got.
他是英格兰最好的朋友之一
Now, English, I want you at the Tower tonight, monitoring this unveiling.
现在，英格力，我要你今晚到伦敦塔，去监视揭幕仪式
Any chink in security, any weakness,
保安措施上的任何缺口
however slight, must be plugged immediately.
不管多细微，都必须立刻堵上
Do we understand each other?
明白我的意思了吗？
- Perfectly, sir. - Good.
- 十分清楚，长官 - 很好
- Oh, yes. And, - uh, English...
- 哦，好的 - 呃，英格力…
we can't afford any mistakes... not tonight.
再也不能出什么篓子了，特别是今晚
The word "mistake, " sir, is not one that appears in my dictionary.
我的字典里没有“篓子”这个词
（伦敦塔）
Fantastic car, sir!
车子很棒，先生！
Mr English, Colonel Sir Anthony Chevenix, head of Royal Security.
英格力先生，上校安东尼·切文尼克斯爵士，皇家安全主管
Ah, Colonel, good evening.
晚上好，上校
- Snipers posted on the roof as per my request? - Thirteen of them.
- 按照我的要求在屋顶上布置狙击手了吗？ - 布置了13个
- Windows? - Refitted with bullet and shatter-proof glass.
- 窗子呢？ - 都换成防弹不破碎的玻璃了
I shall now mingle inconspicuously with the guests.
我现在要混到客人中去，不让人注意到
- Let me know when Her Majesty arrives. - Very good.
- 女王陛下驾到请通知我 - 很好
Shall I mingle with you, sir?
我该和你在一起吗，长官？
Oh, yes, Bough. Once you've checked the roof.
哦，是的， 大宝 你先检查屋顶
Help! Help!
救命！救命！
Well, hello.
你好
Hello yourself.
你也好
Johnny English.
强尼·英格力
Lorna Campbell.
萝娜·坎贝尔
A Bloody Mary, please, not too spicy.
一杯血腥玛丽 ，但别太辣
So, are you here in some professional capacity?
你来这里是因为工作上的需要吗？
I worked on the restoration of the jewels.
我是珠宝修复人员
- Intriguing. - And yourself?
- 很有趣 - 你呢？
If I told you that, I'm afraid I'd have to kill you.
如果我告诉你，我就得杀你灭口了
I'd like to see you try.
那你试试看啊
Monsieur Sauvage, on behalf of Her Majesty,
苏瓦吉先生，我谨代表女王陛下
may I welcome you to the Tower.
欢迎您光临
Merci, monsieur.
谢谢，先生
So, are you here alone, Mr English?
你是一个人来的 英格力先生？
That's how I choose to live my life, Miss Campbell.
我只能选择孤身一人，坎贝尔小姐
Women want safety, security. I can offer them nothing but danger.
女人需要安全，有保障，而我只能带来危险
Some women find danger very attractive.
有些女人觉得危险很有吸引力
Women like you, Miss Campbell?
像你这样的女人吗，坎贝尔？
Women like me expect men like you...
我这样的女人就期待你这样的男人…
to find that out for yourself.
自己找出答案
Hmm.
嗯
Madame.
夫人
Oh, it's for me, actually. Could your rustle up some of those cheesy niblets?
哦，是给我的 你能帮我弄些奶酪玉米粒吗？
Now, where were we?
我们说到哪儿了？
You obviously haven't met our host, Monsieur Sauvage.
很显然，你还没见过我们的主人苏瓦吉先生
No, thank God.
不，感谢上帝
You know, I think I'd rather have my bottom impaled on a giant cactus...
我宁愿坐在仙人掌上，…
than exchange pleasantries with that jumped- up Frenchman.
也不愿和那个法国暴发户说笑话
As far as I'm concerned, the only thing the French should host is an invasion.
据我所知，法国人唯一该招待的就是入侵者
Sorry, can I help?
需要帮忙吗？
Pascal Sauvage, jumped- up Frenchman.
派斯卡·苏瓦吉，法国暴发户
Lorna Campbell. I've been so looking forward to meeting you.
萝娜·坎贝尔 我非常期待见到你
Enchante
[法语] 幸会
But of course! You're Johnny English. I've heard all about you.
哦！ 你是强尼·英格力 久仰，久仰
And between you and me, I'm not so keen on the French myself.
私下说说，我自己也不喜欢法国人
But please don't tell them that.
别告诉别人
Let me go and search for your nibbly cheese bits.
我来帮你去找奶酪玉米粒
- No, no, no. I... - I insist.
- 不，不，不，我… - 让我去吧
The French are, after all, fantastic waiters.
法国人都是天生的侍者
- The best in the world. - Well- But- But...
- 世界上最好的 - 嗯，但 …
- Wait here, and I will wait on you. - No, really. There's no...
- 在这儿等着，让我来招待你 - 不，实际上…
No. Please, please, please!
不，请你！
Hmm. Les Francais.
这些法国人
Ils sont very... n'est- ce pas?
真是非常…呃… 是不是？
Ladies and gentlemen, mesdames est messieurs,
女士们先生们， [法语] 女士们先生们
bienvenus, welcome tonight to this wonderful occasion.
欢迎，欢迎光临今晚这个重要的场合
As we stand here in the Tower of London,
我们所在的伦敦塔
the most famous prison in the world,
是世界上最著名的监狱
where these wonderful jewels will rest safely...
这些奇妙的珠宝
under lock and key,
被安全得锁在这里
I want to thank you...
我要感谢你们…
for giving me this wonderful experience...
给我这次美妙的机会…
to contribute to the restoration of these jewels.
为修复这些珠宝捐款
It was, as we say in France, le top, le best of.
就像我们法国人说的:“好上加好”
And what a beautiful
多美妙的…
It's Colonel Chevenix! He's got a nasty wound, sir. Who hit him?
是切文尼克斯上校！ 他受伤了，谁伤了他？
The assailant. He ran in here.
刺客跑到里面去了
Bough, you guard the door.
大宝，你守住门口
Aha!
啊哈
For God's sake, Bough, don't come in. The man's a maniac!
天哪，大宝，别进来，那家伙是疯子
You don't frighten me!
你吓不了我
Missed!
没打到！
I've managed to subdue the assailant.
我已经制服刺客了
The panic's over. Everything's under control.
恐慌过去了，一切都在控制中
Thank you. And now, ladies and gentlemen,
谢谢，女士们先生们
we should compose ourselves for the arrival of Her Majesty...
我们该镇定下来，等待女王陛下的光临…
and return to the site of our great nation's...
现在回到我们伟大国家…
magnificently restored Crown Jewels.
无与伦比的王室珠宝这里来，它们刚刚被修复
I know. I feel it too.
我知道，我也有这样的感觉
The very symbols of our island nation,
我们这个岛国的象征
so close we could almost reach out and
离我们如此近，伸手可及…
Pray silence for Her Majesty the Queen.
女王陛下驾到，肃静
Oh, where are thejewels?
哦，珠宝在哪儿？
It's an unmitigated disaster, English.
真是彻头彻尾的灾难，英格力
I could n't agree more, sir.
完全同意，长官
Well, we need to get these jewels back, English, and fast.
我们得夺回珠宝，英格力，越快越好
Tell me about this assailant.
告诉我刺客的事情
When they searched the room,
在他们搜查房间时
there was no sign of him.
没有找到他
Well, the man was clearly a professional.
那家伙明显是个职业杀手
He must have escaped while the queen was being sedated.
他一定是在女王来的时候溜走了
But he's the only lead we've got. We have to find him.
但他是唯一的线索，我们必须找到他
Come in. This is... This is Roger from Data Support.
进来，这是… 这是数据部门的罗杰
Please sit down. He'll produce a likeness based on your description.
请坐，他将根据你的描述画一张模拟图
So tell us, what did this man look like?
告诉我们那人长什么样？
Um... well...
嗯，唔…
he was... big.
他… 个头大
- Hair colour? - Um... orange.
- 头发的颜色？ - 嗯…桔色
- Orange? - Mmm. And curly.
- 桔色？ - 嗯，卷发
Well, friZZy, actually. FriZZy sort of thing.
嗯，实际上是紧紧卷曲的的那种
- Frizzy. - An eyepatch.
- 卷得很紧 - 有个眼罩
Broken nose. Very few teeth.
鼻子断了，牙齿不多
Two, I would say, at the most.
最多两颗
And a scar on his cheek...
面颊上有道伤疤…
in the shape... of a banana.
香蕉形状
- Which cheek? - Both cheeks.
- 哪一边？ - 两边都有
They sort of met in the middle.
几乎在中间连到了一起
Are you sure about this, English?
你确信吗，英格力？
Oh, yes, that's him. An uncanny resemblance.
哦，是的，就是这样，太像了
Why, it's just as if he's in the room with us.
为什么，就像他就在这屋里一样
Wow! Look at this, sir. Got all the bells and whistles.
哇，看啊，长官，全套的铃声和汽笛
Never mind about the gad gets. Just focus on the case.
别关心这些小玩意儿，把注意力放到案子上来
（请勿停车  违规者强行拖吊）
Good morning, gentlemen. Thank you very much for waiting.
早上好，先生们，多谢等我
Now, the question that faces us this morning is a simple one.
今早我们面临的只有一个简单的问题
Namely, how did the thieves gain access to this highly secure environment...
就是，盗贼是如何进入如此高度保安的地方…
and then escape with thejewels afterwards?
然后又带着珠宝逃跑的？
A simple question, but one which I believe has a complex answer.
问题很简单，我相信答案却很复杂
- Actually, sir... Uh, please, - Bough. My mind is at work.
- 实际上，长官… - 大宝 我在思考
Now, what you must grasp, gentlemen, is that the master criminal...
你们必须知道，先生们，在一个高明的罪犯眼里…
sees not a room but a series of opportunities.
看到的不是一间房间，而是一连串的机会
Should I go in through the window?
我该从窗子进去吗？
Possibly.
也许
- Should I drop down from the ceiling? - Actually, sir...
- 我该从天花板落下来吗？ - 实际上，长官…
There's one thing I think we can be fairly confident about,
只有一件事情可以确信
that is that they didn't come up through the floor...
他们不是从地板下进来的…
I've got you, sir.
我扶住你了，长官
That's all right. Just come my way, Bough.
没关系，朝我这边来，大宝
- That'll bring me right over the hole, sir. - There's no need to panic.
- 那我就要跨过地洞了，长官 - 没必要恐慌
Can you see the bottom yet, Bough?
见到底了吗，大宝？
Not yet, sir. The shaft appears to be narrowing.
还没有，下面越来越窄
I'm just a little bit worried I might get stuck.
我有点担心会被卡住
Trust me, Bough. You won't get stuck if you just keep moving.
相信我，大宝 不会的，继续下
Yes, sir.
是，长官
I'm okay, sir.
我没事，长官
Are you at the bottom now, Bough?
到底了吗，大宝？
No, I am in fact stuck now, sir.
没，我实际上被卡住了
Oh, for God's sake, Bough. Stay there! I'm coming down.
哦，上帝，大宝 别动，我下来了
Uh, I'm not especially sure that's a good idea, sir.
我觉得这不是个好主意，长官
Don't worry.
别担心
Be careful, sir!
小心，长官！
Gently does it.
慢慢地
Sir?
长官？
- Are you all right, sir? - Yes. I landed on something quite soft.
- 你没事吧，长官？ - 是的，我脚下某个柔软的东西
- That was me, sir. - Oh, good.
- 你脚下是我，长官 - 哦，很好
What now?
现在干什么？
There's no way back up there, that's for sure.
只能肯定的是，会不去了
But this must lead somewhere.
但这一定通向某处
I'm slightly uncomfortable in the dark, sir.
我在黑的地方有点不舒服，长官
There's nothing to worry about, Bough.
没什么可担心的，大宝
It may be pitch black,
也许一片漆黑
but we can still see.
但我们还是能看见
Can we, sir? How?
能吗，长官？ 怎么看？
The Bedouin monks of the Al Maghreb mountains...
阿尔马格来伯山上的贝多因僧人…
developed a system of sonic chanting.
发明了一种声波圣歌
- I see, sir. - The sound of their chanting...
- 我明白了，长官 - 他们的歌声…
would bounce back off any obstacles,
遇到障碍物会反弹
and using their highly tuned ears...
用他们高度音准的耳朵…
they could paint a mental picture of the path ahead.
他们能在脑子里面形成前面道路的图像
- Brilliant, sir. - However, you must always sing in E-flat.
- 太棒了，长官 - 但，你的歌声必须保持降E调
∮ E-flat, E-flat, E-flat ∮
∮ E音调，E音调，E音调 ∮
∮ Thank you for the music, The songs I'm singing ∮
∮ 感谢你，这音乐，也感谢我所吟唱的歌 ∮
- Is it working, sir? - Extremely well, thank you, Bough.
- 有效吗，长官？ - 很好，谢谢你，大宝
∮ Thanks for all the joy that... ∮
∮ 感谢所有的欢乐，因为… ∮
You all right, sir? I think I can see something, sir.
你没事吗，长官？ 我想我看见了，长官
Oh, yeah. Come on.
哦，好啊，继续
Here is the long one.
这是个长的
It is a long one.
长的
Careful.
小心
- I knew it. - Shall we call for backup, sir?
- 我知道 - 我们要叫支援吗，长官？
What? And watch some fat- bottomed bobby make our arrest for us?
什么？ 看着那些胖警察来代替我们逮捕他们？
I don't think so.
我可不这么想
Good morning, gentlemen. MI7 at your service.
早上好， 军情七处 为您服务
Observe, Bough, the dull incompetence of the criminal mind.
看看，大宝，这些迟钝无能的家伙，
It can never hope to match our level of technical expertise.
他们的脑子永远达不到我们这种专家级的水准
- You've got it. - What do we do now, sir?
- 好了 - 我们现在怎么办，长官？
Watch and learn, Bough.
好好学着点，大宝
They're too far ahead of us.
他们在我们前面太远了
Have faith, Bough. They're heading south.
有点信心，大宝 他们往南去了
- There they are, sir! - Just as I thought.
- 他们在那儿，长官！ - 不出所料
Hang on tight, Bough.
抓好了
We're never gonna catch them in this.
开这车永远赶不上他们
- Take the wheel, Bough. I'm getting in the Aston. - Sir?
- 你来开，大宝 我到后面去拿车 - 长官？
Change places, Bough. I'm getting out the other side.
换位置，大宝 我走另一边出去
Sir?
长官？
Set, Bough. Take me up.
停，大宝 把我调起来
Swing me out, Bough!
甩出去，大宝！
- Whoa. - Down.
- 啊 - 下
Up! Up!
上！ 上！
Sorry!
抱歉！
Bough, pull out!
大宝，靠边停
Those idiots are right behind us. Faster!
那些白痴就在我们后面，再开快点！
（时速:63英里）
Uh- huh.
啊，哈
Drop me here, Bough!
把我放在这里，大宝！
Ow! Oh.
哦
No! No! No!
不，不！
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
哦，不，不，不，不，不
They're turning into the Brompton Cemetery.
他们转向公墓去了
Get here as soon as you can. I'm going in.
快赶去那儿，我先进去了
In a wheelchair. But Geoffrey overcame these terrible disabilities...
尽管坐在轮椅上 杰弗里克服了残迹带来的种种不便…
with that simple resilience and sunny optimism...
保持着乐观愉快的心情…
that so warmed all of us who knew him,
温暖着我们每个认识他的人
spending the rest of his life in the service...
他把余生贡献给了…
of the poor and disabled of this parish.
这个教区的穷人和残疾人
It's very good. Really very good.
很好，真是太棒了
It's very entertaining. Who's that?
不，不，请继续，抱歉打断
- It's very entertaining. - Who's that?
- 很有意思 - 他是谁？
That priest act of yours should keep the other prisoners entertained for hours.
你扮牧师的表演会让牢里其他犯人乐上几个小时的
Oh, I'm so sorry. Where are my manners? Johnny English,
哦，抱歉，我的礼貌哪里去了？强尼·英格力
British Secret Service, and you are all under arrest.
英国秘密特工，你们都被捕了
I must say you've done this whole thing very well.
我得说，你的表演很棒
The attention to detail is excellent.
对细节的留意很出色
You, the grieving granny, you're very convincing.
你，伤心的老奶奶，很有说服力
Oh, look. Real tears. Do you get paid extra for that?
哦，看啊，真的眼泪 你会得到额外奖励吗？
Ahh, what we're all here for.
这就是我们都要的东西
I know! Why don't we take a look inside?
我知道！ 为什么不看看里面？
Oh, you've nailed it down!
哦，你们已经上了钉子了
Why would you do that?
为什么这么做？
I know you're gonna come back in two weeks and dig it up again.
我知道你们会过两个星期再来把它挖出来
Now, what are you playing in this little vignette of deceit and villainy?
你在这个欺骗和邪恶编织的小插曲里扮演什么角色？
I'm the hearse driver.
我是灵车司机
- You're the hearse driver? - Yes, sir.
- 你是灵车司机？ - 是的，长官
Ah!Aha!
啊哈！
There you are... Gunther.
你在这里… 贡特
Uh, I do hope he hasn't made a nuisance of himself.
呃，我很希望他没有惹你们讨厌
I'm Doctor, um...Bough,
我是大宝医生…
of the Lunatic Response Unit.
精神病院的
I'm afraid Gunther here wasn't supposed to be released until 2028.
恐怕贡特 要等到2028年才能被放出来
Isn't that right, Gunther?
是不是啊，贡特？
Yes, yes, there's been the most monumental cock- up.
是的，是的，真是非常糟糕
Um, if you'll excuse me, with the deepest respect,
呃，请原谅，谨表示深深的敬意
utmost sympathy.
我无限同情
Uh, he hasn't urinated on anyone, has he?
呃，他没有向你们撒尿吧？
- No. - No, no.
- 不 - 不，没有
That's a blessing. Are you gonna give me the gun, Gunther?
这是葬礼祝词 把枪给我好吗？
There. That wasn't too difficult, was it?
不是很难，是不是？
Are you going to come home now?
你现在回家吗？
Oh... in the van! Yes, we are going in the van.
哦… 面包车！我们去上面包车
Yes, yes. Vroom, vroom.
好的，好的 卟咙，卟咙
- Vroom, vroom. Vroom, vroom. - Yes. Yeah.
- 卟咙，卟咙 卟咙，卟咙 - 好的，好的
Yes. He's waving good- bye. Good- bye, everyone.
他在挥手道别，再见了
- Good- bye. - Good- bye, Gunther.
- 再见 - 再见，贡特
Mind the nice dead people. There we go.
继续你们的葬礼 我们走
Oh, we'lljust go to the path here. There. Big step.
走这边的路，那边，一个大台阶
It's a graveyard. It's where they bring people...
这是墓地 人们到这里来…
Yes, all right. You can stop now.
好了，现在可以不装了
- For appearances, I'll just hold your arm. - Just keep walking.
- 表面上，我还抓着你的胳膊 - 一直走
In fact, run, run, run!
跑，跑，跑！
I can't believe I've done this.
不敢相信我成功了
I mean, I really cannot believe I've done this!
不敢相信真的成功了！
You see, 200 years ago,
你们看，200 年前
my family should have inherited the throne of England,
我的家族应该继承英格兰的王位
but they were cast aside.
但他们被抛弃了
Well, in a few very short days,
再过几天
it will be back where it belongs.
他就要物归原主了
（派斯卡爱德华苏瓦吉）
With me.
也就是我
Shall I try it on? Yes? No? Maybe?
我是不是该试试，是还是不是？也许？
To make you king, we need the archbishop of Canterbury to do that.
你的加冕必须由坎特伯雷大主教主持
The archbishop of Canterbury...
坎特伯雷大主教
is being taken care of even as we speak. TARGET ACQUIRED
在我们说话的时候，已经搞定了 目标锁定
（目标锁定）
（面部立体扫描完成）
There's only one thing, sir. What are we going to do about English?
还有一件事，长官 我们怎么处置英格力？
If I were you, I wouldn't worry too much about English.
如果我是你，我就不会担心他英格力
He is no threat to us. I had his flat bugged.
他对我们不是危险
Clearly, the aptly named English is a fool.
很明显，这个叫英格力是个傻瓜
He might be a fool, but he's a fool who keeps showing up.
他也许是傻瓜，但他总是出现
Well, the next time he shows up,
那么，下次他出现的时候
eliminate him.
灭了他
Thank you.
谢谢
Dieter Klein and Klaus Vendetta, sir.
迪特克·克来恩和克劳斯·范德塔，长官
Released from prison six months ago. 327 convictions between them.
6个月前刚被释放，他们一共有327项罪名
Armed robbery, grievous bodily harm...
持械抢劫，严重身体伤害…
and combined parking fines of more than 400...
还有400张违章停车罚单…
Uh, yes, all right. Thank you, Bough. I think we get the picture.
好的，谢谢，大宝 我想我们已经明白了
The point is, sir, that Vendetta and Klein...
问题是，长官，范德塔和克来恩…
are both in the employ of Monsieur Sauvage.
都是苏瓦吉的雇员
- Pascal Sauvage? - Precisely, sir.
- 派斯卡·苏瓦吉？ - 正是，长官
But you're not suggesting Sauvage is involved?
你意思是苏瓦吉牵扯在内？
I think he's more than just involved, sir.
我想不仅仅是牵扯的问题，长官
I'm convinced he's up to his French neck in it.
我确信他是主谋
Don't be absurd. Sauvage employs thousands of people.
别蠢了 苏瓦吉雇佣了几千员工
Just because two of them are villains doesn't mean that he is.
其中两个员工是恶棍，并不表示他也是恶棍
I want him discounted from this investigation immediately.
我希望立刻停止调查他
Yes, sir.
是的，长官
All right. Tonight I shall be at Sauvage's reception forthe new French ambassador.
今晚，我要参加苏瓦吉招待新任法国大使的晚会
Any developments, you can reach me there.
有什么发现，可以到那里找我
Apart from that, I don't want you within a hundred miles of the man.
除了这以外，我不希望你靠近他方圆100英里以内
Absolutely, sir.
一定，长官
Requisition order... MI7 quartermasters for immediate supply.,
征用命令… 立刻向军情七处军需官要求供应
one military transport plane, fully fueled,
一架军用运输机，加满燃料
with permission for nighttime city over flight
还要夜间城市上空飞行的许可证
two night camouflage parachutes, plus reserves,
两个夜间伪装降落伞，加上储备
plus neoprene bodysuits, twice, in black.
还有橡胶紧身衣两件，黑色的
I've never liked the navy blue.
我不喜欢海军兰的
And a 40- inch chest for me 'cause I need the sleeve length.
一件40英寸的防弹衣，因为我要那种袖长
- Morning, Felch. - Morning.
- 早上好，菲尔齐 - 早上好
Oh, and two Special Forces signet rings,
哦，两个特种部队的印章指环
primed and colour- coded.
有底色的而且使用色标的
- What's all this for? - For tonight's operation.
- 这些干什么用的？ - 今晚的行动用
We're going to break into Sauvage's headquarters.
我们要打入苏瓦吉的总部
- But Pegasus said... - Let me worry about Pegasus.
- 但柏伽索斯说… - 我来对付柏伽索斯
I know that Sauvage is behind all this,
我知道苏瓦吉是幕后的黑手
and tonight we're going to get the evidence.
今晚我们就是要拿证据
- Is something wrong, sir? - Did that sound like Felch to you?
- 有什么问题吗，长官？ - 刚才那声音是菲尔齐的吗？
Bough
大宝…
You, upstairs.
你到楼上去
Ow.
哦
He's on the upper level, sir.
能看见他吗，大宝？
他在上面一层，长官
Got him.
他跑不了了
And like a coiled viper... he strikes.
像盘曲的毒蛇… 出击
So what you're saying, sir, is there must have been two of them?
你怎么认为，长官，一定有两个人？
Oh, at least, Bough. Possibly four.
起码两个，大宝 也许4个
I wonder why I didn't see them.
真奇怪，我怎么没看见
You mustn't dwell on your mistakes.
你不该停留在你的失误上
- You must learn from them, then move on. - Yes, sir.
- 你必须从中吸取教训，向前进 - 是的，长官
- So where were you, sir? - Just drop it, Bough!
- 你当时在哪里，长官？ - 别谈这个了，大宝！
- Aah! What is it, sir? - That bike.
- 啊！ 那是什么，长官？ - 那摩托
You get things sorted out for tonight.
你把今晚要的东西准备好
Well, well, we meet again.
啊，我们又见面了
Mr English. What a pleasant surprise.
英格力先生 真是个惊喜
I wondered when you might show up again.
我正想你什么时候出现呢
On the contrary, Miss Campbell. It is not I who keeps showing up. It's you.
正相反，坎贝尔小姐 不是我，是你不停出现
Do you like sushi?
你喜欢寿司吗？
Hmm?
恩？
Oh, sushi! I practically live off the stuff.
哦，寿司，我几乎以此为生
You might say the mysteries of the Orient are no mystery to me.
你可以说东方的神秘事物对我一点都不神秘
- Sake? - Ah. Sake.
- 清酒？ - 啊，清酒
Cheers.
干杯
May all your daughters be born with three bottoms.
祝你女儿都长三个屁股
Now then, perhaps you can explain how it is...
现在，也许你可以解释一下…
that I run into you at two crime scenes...
为什么两次在犯罪现场都遇到你…
and then can't find any record of you on a single government computer.
而且在任何一个政府的计算机上都找不到你的记录
Shouldn't you ask the government that?
你为什么不去问政府？
I am the government and I'm asking you.
我就是政府的人，我在问你
Let me.
我来帮你
Mmm. You're brave.
恩，你很勇敢
They say that sea urchin's the ultimate acquired taste.
他们说海胆是终极美味
Hmm. It's a personal favourite of mine.
嗯，那是我的个人最爱
I think people are put off by how it feeds through its bottom.
我想人们因为它从肛门进食所以觉得它恶心
Would you excuse me for a moment?
失陪一下
Excuse me. Sorry. I'm from MI7. Sorry. I'm a secret agent.
抱歉，我是军情七处的 抱歉，我是秘密特工
- Everything set, Bough? - Just about, sir.
- 一切就绪了，大宝？ - 快了，长官
Actually, sir, do you mind if I run through the plan one more time?
长官，你介意我再温习一下计划吗？
- No, no. - These are the two buildings here.
- 不，不 - 那里有两栋建筑
This one is ourtarget, Sauvage's headquarters, next to City Hospital.
这就是我们的目标，苏瓦吉的总部，在市医院旁边
I jump first and land on the south side of the roof,
我先跳，降落在屋顶的南边
abseil down 14 floors and cut through this window here.
用绳子降落14层楼，从这个窗子进去
I then land on the east side and abseil down 12 floors.
我降落在东边，用绳子降12层楼
Where you wait for my signal that I've disabled the alarm system.
你就在那儿等我排除警报系统以后给你信号
- Yes. - You them break i nto this window here,
- 是的 - 你从这个窗子进去
work your way along the secure corridor and penetrate Sauvage's office.
沿着安全走廊走，进入苏瓦吉的办公室
- Yes, yes. - Is that okay, sir?
- 是的，是的 - 那样能行吗，长官？
It's been okay ever since I thought up the idea, Bough.
从我想到这个主意起就没有问题，大宝
Oh, I nearly forgot, sir. Your laser beacon.
哦，我差点忘记了，长官 你的激光信号器
- My what? - Your laser beacon!
- 什么？ - 你的激光信号器！
It'll guide you onto Sauvage's building.
它可以引导你降落到苏瓦吉屋子
Your dependence on hardware really does amuse me, Bough.
你对硬件的依赖让我好笑，大宝
I've been dropped into the Kalahari Desert...
我曾经降落在格拉哈里沙漠…
carrying nothing more than a toothbrush and a packet of sherbet lemons,
什么也没有带，除了一把牙刷和一包柠檬果子露
and I still found my way to Bulawayo before Ramadan.
但我仍然在斋月前到达了布拉瓦约
So thank you, Bough, but no thank you.
所以，谢谢你，大宝，但也没什么好谢的
Bough, go!
大宝，走！
Geronimo!
杰利连摩！
Fandango!
方丹果！
Ai- yi- yi.
啊！
Right.
好了
Alarm's disabled, sir.
警报解除，长官
Roger that, Bough.
收到，大宝
（实验室）
（脑神经科）
This is worse than I thought, Bough.
比我想的要糟，大宝
Sauvage has got some kind of laboratory set up here.
苏瓦吉在这里搞了格实验室
God knows what kind of sick operation he's running.
鬼知道他们在这里干什么
My God, what have they done to you?
上帝，他们把你怎么了？
They've taken some of my blood.
取了点血
- Bastards! - It's only for tests.
- 杂种！ - 这是为了做试验
Of course it is. Come on, my friend.
当然是，跟我来，朋友
Let's get you out of here before they take anything else.
在他们取掉你身上其他东西前逃出去
Good evening, Dr Frankenstein.
晚上好，弗兰肯斯坦博士（形容一位科学家在合成人兽合成体）
Come on This way, please.
请这边走
Come on. I haven't got all night.
来啊，夜还长着呢
And you, you angels of death.
还有你们，死亡天使
About turn. Come on, let's go.
转身，走
Come on, come on. Keep moving.
快点，快点，继续走
Come on. Over there. I know what you're doing here. And you.
到那边去，我知道你们在这里干什么 还有你
Come on. Quicker. Quicker. Over there.
快点，快啊，到那边去
Now then,
现在
perhaps you could direct me to your evil paymaster.
也许你也要带我去见你们的魔鬼老板
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
You know exactly what I'm talking about.
你知道得很清楚我说什么
Where is the office of Pascal Sauvage?
派斯卡·苏瓦吉的办公室在哪儿？
Are you coming over here in a minute, sir?
你马上就到了吗，长官？
I'm from MI7.
我是军情七处的
This has been a test of your emergency response systems,
这是在测试你们的紧急发应系统
and I have to say you've all done extremely well.
我得说，你们干得很好
Right. Well, I'll leave you to it.
好吧，那就丢给你们自己管了
And, uh, get well soon.
啊，早日康复
Oh, God!
哦，上帝！
Sir. Sir.
长官 长官
Did you just land on the wrong building?
你降错地方了？
I did a precautionary sweep of the immediate environment.
我对附近的环境做了一个预防性的检查
Right.
是的
- And everything was fine. - Good.
- 一切顺利 - 很好
Okay, let's go.
好的，我们走
I will be downstairs at the reception
我到楼下的招待会去…
- That's far enough. - Well, good evening.
- 你们走得太远了 - 晚上好
- Perhaps you'd like this as well. - What is it?
- 也许你也喜欢这个 - 是什么？
- Let me show you. - Aah!
- 我来给你看 - 啊！
Well executed, Bough, but completely redundant.
很有效，大宝，但完全多余
- How do you mean, sir? - Super-strength muscle relaxant.
- 什么意思，先生？ - 超级力量的肌肉松弛剂
When he wakes up, he'll be as floppy as a damp old sock.
即便他醒来也是手无缚鸡之力
What's this?
是什么？
That's the face of the archbishop of Canterbury.
那是坎特伯雷大主教的脸
What are they doing?
他们在干什么？
What's this got to do with the Crown Jewels?
这跟王室珠宝有何关联？
（天国已近  赶快加油）
Bough.
大宝
English.
英格力
A people whose empire once covered...
有一个人，他的帝国曾…
one quarter of the surface of the earth.
覆盖地球的四分之一面积
Alas, no longer.
可以，已不再是了
My friends ask me, "Pascal, how can you be so interested...
我的朋友们问我:"派斯卡，你怎么对追溯…
in such a backward, grotty little country?"
过去的小王国那么有兴趣？"
My answer is simple.. the queen.
我的回答很简单… 女王
The queen has more power in hertiny white gloves...
我们的女王比全世界上…
than any other head of state in the entire world.
任何一个国家的元首都富有权利
She can declare war or make peace,
她可以宣战或选择和平，
and most intriguingly...
最具魅力的是…
she can seiZe any piece of land which takes her fancy.
她只要愿意就能将她的土地拆分
Ofcourse, the queen never uses...
当然了，女王从不用…
the enormous power afforded to her.
这巨大的力量来自己获利
But imagine someone who would use that power.
但设想下有人用了那力量
Imagine, say, me.
设想一下，说，我
But how could he do that, sir? How could he make himself king?
他怎么做到的，先生？他怎么弄得自己像个国王？
The archbishop.
大主教
Ow.
哦
Hands up. There's a good fellow.
举起手来 那样很好
Heavily armed for a late night at the office.
于夜晚重装身处办公室
You fool, English. You'll never get out of the building alive.
你个笨蛋，英格力 你绝对无法活着离开这儿
I'd save your breath for my questioning.
你省省口舌，还是回答我的问题吧
I'm not telling you anything.
我不会跟是说任何事情
Incorrect.
不对
Sodium pentothal.
钠喷妥撒
I won't lie to you. It's a truth serum.
我不骗你 这可是会让人讲真话的麻药
Now then, why does Sauvage want to have himself crowned?
那么，为什么苏瓦吉想要加冕他自己？
You have no idea what's going on here, do you?
对于这儿的进程你一无所知，对吗？
It would be funny if it wasn't so...
如果那不是那么的… 那定会蛮有趣的
What?
什么？
- He's talking gibberish, sir. - I can hear that.
- 他开始胡言乱语了，先生 - 我听到了
- He's collapsed onto me, sir. - I can see that.
- 他倒在我身上了，先生 - 我看到了
- You don't think you could've got the syringes mixed up? - What?
- 你确定你没有把注射管子搞错？ - 什么？
Given the guard outside truth serum and given Klein the muscle relaxant?
给外头的门卫注射能说真话的麻药，给克来恩注射松弛剂？
Aah!
啊！
Don't be ridiculous, Bough. I think I know my right from my left.
别开玩笑了，大宝 我想我左右手还是会分的
- Sir? - Oh, bugger it.
- 长官？ - 哦，他妈的
Bough, take "flodd."
大宝，去拿"flodd"
- Take what, sir? - Flodd, "Schlage."
- 拿什么啊，长官？ - "Flodd" "Schlage"
- I'm not quite getting that second word, sir. - Schlaaaagh!
- 我没听清第二个词是什么，长官 - "Schlaaaagh！"
- Write it down, sir. - Schlaaaagh!
- 写下来，长官 - "Schlaaaagh！"
Yes!
没错！
C. C- A- Uh...
"C" C- A… 啊…
Car! Take the car! We came by plane.
车子！坐车！我们是做飞机来的
Bugger off!
走开！
Hold it right there.
在那儿别动
- What's wrong with them? - I'm not telling you.
- 他们怎么啦？ - 我不会跟你们说的
Wrong answer.
错误回答
What is it with you two?
你们俩在搞什么？
Huh?
啊？
Let's get outta here.
我们快离开这儿
Sorry, but who are you, exactly?
不好意思，但你是谁呢？
Special Agent Campbell. I'm attached to Interpol in Paris.
特工坎贝尔 我隶属于巴黎的国际刑警组织
We've been watching Sauvage for months.
我们监视苏瓦吉好几个月了
Why?
为什么？
Because every major convict released from a Sauvage prison in six months...
因为大多数在这六个月内从苏瓦吉的监狱里…
has been employed by one of his companies.
释放的犯人已被其的一间公司雇用
We believe he's recruiting them for a major criminal conspiracy.
我们认为他重新召集那帮人是为了个重大的犯罪事件
We just don't know what yet.
我们就只是不明白要干什么
- What did he say? - Pegasus!
- 他说什么？ - 柏伽索斯！
We have to report to Pegasus!
我们必须向柏伽索斯报告！
Oh, no, sir. No, no, no.
哦，不，先生 不，不，不
- How do we get out of here? - Hey, you two!
- 我们怎么从这儿出去？ - 嘿，你们两个！
How do we get out of here? Hey, you two!
你对我所做的真的有伤害
Yeah. Sorry about that. How do we get out of here without being seen?
是的 不好意思，我们如何才能不被发现的离开这儿？
Okay.
好的
Left by the fountain,
沿着喷泉的左侧走
right by the fire exit,
再顺着防火出口右边走
to the elevator at the end.
一直走到电梯尽头
- Thank you. - Oh, my God.
- 谢谢 - 哦，我的天哪
Nice job, Bough.
干得好，大宝
Left, sir. Left!
左边，长官，左边！
Sir, you can't go to Sauvage's reception in this state.
长官，你不能就这样去苏瓦吉的招待会
The effect of the drug has practically worn off.
药物的作用即将用尽
I'm "fline"
我很好…
schline... uh, "gline"...
真的很好… 啊，非常好…
- Monsieur. - Ah. Thank you.
- 先生 - 谢谢
- Would you like another? - Please.
- 再来一杯吗？ - 好的
Thank you.
谢谢
What in God's name...
你搞什么啊…
Ah, Foreign "Sebretarary."
啊，外交大臣
Um
嗯…
Aah!
啊！
hall we dance?
我们跳舞吧？
Excuse me, sir. I'm very sorry to interrupt...
打搅了，先生 很抱歉打扰了您…
Pascal, how nice to see you again.
派斯卡，见到你真是太高兴了
- Enjoying the party? - Oh, splendid affair.
- 玩得开心吗？ - 哦，开心得不得了
I was until I was informed that your man English...
我是来通知你，你的人英格力…
and his curious boyfriend here have spent the evening...
和他那古怪的朋友一整夜的功夫…
breaking into my office and assaulting my staff.
闯进我的办公室，打伤我的人
- Is this true, Bough? - Well, we...
- 这是真的吗，大宝？ - 嗯，我们…
What do you think you're up to?
你认为你做了些什么？
- Sir, if I could just offe - Go home, Bough!
- 长官，如果我能提供… - 回家去，大宝！
Now!
现在！
I gave you direct orders not to meddle with Sauvage.
我早就命令过你不要惊动苏瓦吉
What do you do?
那你干了些什么？
Break into his office
闯进他的办公室
and assault two of his staff.
打伤他的两个手下
Then you march in here,
然后你来到了这儿
loaded with God knows what,
不知道哪根筋不对
and insult the foreign secretary.
冒犯了外交大臣
I haven't encountered such behaviour in Whitehall in 30 years.
30年里我在政府里从没见过如此的举动
- But - There are no "buts, " English.
- 但是… - 没有但是，英格力
You're off the case. Your security clearance is hereby cancelled.
你不用再跟这案子了 你的安全通行就此终结
After a three- month leave of absence, you will return at your old grade.
3个月的休假之后，你将返回原级
And I hope never to hear your name again.
我希望再也见不到你
English has seen too much.
英格力知道得太多了
We go to plan "B."
执行B计划
Get rid of the fake archbishop...
揭穿这假的大主教…
and green- light the visit to Her Majesty.
绿灯访问女王陛下
Then this pathetic country can humiliate itself...
然后这可怜的国家将会因官方上给我加冕…
by crowning me officially.
而自我羞辱
（女王在桑德灵厄姆的住处）
That's a letter of abdication...
这是封让位证明…
renouncing your claims to the throne...
关于断绝你与王位关系…
and the claims of your entire family.
以及你整个家族关系的证明
Sign it.
签字
（逊位书）
Never.
决不
Yes?
喂？
Prime Minister, sorry to call so late,
总理先生，抱歉那么晚打电话给你
but I'm afraid the queen is abdicating.
但我担心女王就要让位了
What?
什么？
Abdicated? But that's not possible.
让位？但那是不可能的
I only wish that were true.
我只希望那是真的
- Let me talk to her. Maybe she just... - Pascal, she's gone.
- 让我跟她说 也许她只是… - 派斯卡，她已经走了
My people have spent the last 10 hours...
我的人已经花了10个小时…
trying to track down the rightful heir to the throne...
来确认王位的合法继承人…
and they've come up with a name, which they've double- checked.
他们提出个人的名字，这是他们双手赞同的
Who is it?
是谁？
- It's you. - No!
- 是你 - 不
In the wake of the return of the Crown Jewels...
清晨王室珠宝返还到…
to a police station in North London,
伦敦北部的一警察局
Pascal Sauvage has requested that his coronation...
派斯卡·苏瓦吉的加冕仪式…
take place this Thursday.
将于本周四举行
In the House, the prime minister said he was looking forward to the ceremony...
在议院，总理说他期盼着这场盛典…
and he believed that Monsieur Sauvage will make a fine king...
他相信苏瓦吉绅士将会是个好国王…
and will bring all that is best about modern Europe to our ancient institutions.
他会给我们旧有的制度带来最好的现代欧洲的制度
Get your car keys. We've got work to do.
带上你的车钥匙我们有活要干了
- Miss Campbell. - Sauvage is heading back to France.
- 坎贝尔小姐 - 苏瓦吉正以首脑的姿态回法国去
He's invited 13 of the richest criminal masterminds in the world to meet him there.
他邀请了世界上最富有的13个犯罪策划到那儿见他
I'm sorry, Miss Campbell. I'm off the case.
对不起，坎贝尔小姐 我不再跟这个案子了
It's been reassigned.
案子被重新分配了
I know. Reassigned to me.
我知道 重新分配给了我
- I want you with me. - Just leave me alone.
- 我想要你跟我一块儿 - 就让我一个人待着吧
Are you gonna sit here in this grotty flat feeling sorry foryourself?
你是愿意坐在这令人不爽的公寓里自怨自艾呢？
Or are you gonna get out there and save your country?
还是愿意出去拯救你的国家呢？
I'm gonna sit in the flat.
我要待在这公寓里
- Johnny, this is ridiculous. - I'm a spent force.
- 强尼，这太可笑了 - 我是个废人
Spent, my ass.
废啊，笨蛋
Ow.
哦
Will... you... please... stop?
请…你… 住…手？
I'll just be a minute.
我要迟一会儿
（新王派斯卡苏瓦吉登基典礼）
（法国北部）
It'll be nightfall in an hour. Then we can strike out for the chateau.
一个小时候就是黄昏 接着我们就能朝城堡进发了
The fact is, the moment Sauvage gets that crown on his head,
可问题是，那一时刻苏瓦吉把王冠戴在头上
he'll be able to do whatever he likes with the country that I love,
他就能对我所爱的国家为所欲为了
and that is why you and I have got to stop him.
那就是为何你我要来阻止他的原因
- Relishing the thought? - Something like that.
- 考虑那个想法？ - 差不多
I suppose you've made love to lots of women, haven't you, Johnny?
我猜你跟很多女人做过爱，不是吗，强尼？
Uh Uh, well, you know,
啊，嗯，你知道啦，
one does one's best.
某人未必尽其全力
It's just...
就只是…
Well, it's been three years since my fiance left me,
嗯，我未婚夫离开我已经三年了
and since then I haven't made love to anyone.
从那之后我就没跟任何人做过爱
But then I met you...
但我遇到你后…
and I felt this... hunger...
我感觉到了… 这种冲动…
deep down inside.
在蠢蠢欲动
I wanted to say things to you, I wanted to do things to you...
我想要跟你说些事情，我想跟你做些什么事…
that I haven't wanted to do in a very, very, very long time.
那种事我已经很久很久没想要做过了
What, uh...
啊…
What sort of things are we talking about?
我们在谈些什么事情啊？
Things like punching you in the face,
关于在你脸上拍击的事
kicking you in the backside for being such a pompous, know- nothing asshole.
关于在你后面华而不实的偷袭你的事
But then I started to see beyond the idiot that everybody else saw.
但然后我开始看到脱俗的事物
I started to see the man on the inside...
我开始看到里面有个人…
who was determined to do his duty,
他坚守他的职责
no matter what or who lay in his way.
无论遇到什么困难
And I began to feel other things for him,
接着我开始感觉到了些其它的东西
to want to do other things for him.
我想为他做些其它的事
Things...
事情…
involving plastic toys and soft cheese?
包括塑胶玩具和软干酪？
- What? - What? What?
- 什么？ - 什么？什么？
You're toying with me. You're telling me to stop in the gentlest way you know how.
你在戏耍我 你正在叫我不要这么温柔的对你
No. N- N- No...
不是的…
You're such a special person...
你是个特殊的人…
not to take advantage of me while I'm vulnerable.
当我易受攻击时不利用我
- No...  Well - So thank you...
- 不，可是… - 谢谢你…
for being such a gentleman.
是如此的有绅士风度
Not at all.
那没什么
I know what you're thinking, Miss Campbell.
我知道你在想什么，坎贝尔小姐
If we don't pull this off, God knows what might happen to England.
如果我们不阻止这一切，天知道英国会发生什么
Actually, I was thinking there must be a betterway in than that pipe.
实际上，我在想那肯定有比那管子更好的途径
Well, there isn't.
可是没有
I've analysed it from every angle, and this is the best option.
我已经从各个方面分析过了，这是最好的选择
I'll go in first, and if it's a clear way through, I'll call down.
我先上，如果路线很明确，我就联络你
Johnny.
强尼
- Be careful. - I'm always careful.
- 小心点 - 我一直很小心
Ohh.
哦
Gentlemen.
先生们
In a few hours time...
再过几小时时间…
I will become the next king of England.
我将成为下任英国国王
Oh, no.
哦，不
- How did you get here? - Up the ladder.
- 你怎么进来这儿的？ - 爬梯子
Pull yourself together. It's only a bit of poo.
这没什么，就是有一点臭罢了
Oh! Oh, it's cold! It's cold!
哦！好冷啊！好冷啊！
What is the one commodity...
世上从没见过用尽的…
the world never seems to run out of?
货品是什么？
Criminals, gentlemen.
是罪犯，先生们
Lawbreakers.
犯法着
Every nation in the world struggles...
世界上每个国家为解决这个问题…
with the issue of overcrowded prisons.
而建造监狱
So, what do we do with all these villains?
那么，我们与所有这些坏人做什么呢？
Find the solution to that problem...
找到解决那个问题的方法…
and the governments of the world would pay you through their nose.
世界上的政府们将会永远酬谢你们
Fortunately, I have found a solution.
很幸运，我找到了个解决的办法
We empty every prison on the entire planet,
我们清空这个星球上所有的监狱
we take the resulting tidal wave of human scum...
我们把这群人类的渣滓…
and we put it here.
汇总到这儿来
The moment I am crowned king,
此刻我加冕为国王
I will turn England into the largest prison...
我将把英国变成世界历史上…
in the history of the world.
最大的监狱
210, 000 square miles...
21万平方英里…
of prime real estate...
作为最初的地产…
conveniently separated from true civilization...
方便的从人类真实文明中分开…
by 20 miles of ocean...
用20英里的海洋…
- and soon to be available... - Come on.
- 不久全世界就有可能… - 走吧
for the entire world to dump its human waste in.
把他们的犯人关到这里来
According to current projections,
根据潮流的设计，
we will not run out of prison space for the next 500 years.
我们可以使用该监狱至少500年
So, toni ght one, and only one, of you...
所以今晚，你们当中将仅有一个人…
So, tonight one, and only one, of you...
可以赢得49%的机会…
of this venture.
离开这儿
So that's his little game. We must get hold of that DVD.
所以那就是他的小把戏 我们必须得到那DVD
But how, Johnny? There's only two of us.
但怎么做呢，强尼？我们就只有两个人
You're young, Miss Campbell, and inexperienced.
你还年轻，坎贝尔小姐，而且没有经验
What you seem to have forgotten is that...
你看起来忘记了…
nobody knows we are here.
没人知道我们在这儿
At our disposal we have the vital element of surprise.
我们该作出至关重要的决定
Now, my plan is simple but effective.
现今，我的计划简单但有效
I shall drop from the gallery at this end of the room
我将在房间尽头的走廊降落
and take Sauvage prisoner.
然后逮住苏瓦吉
You will then enter from the far door,
你接着从远门端进来
cutting off any means of escape.
切断任何逃跑路线
Then, using Sauvage as a hostage,
然后，将苏瓦吉作为人质
we'll get the hell out of here. Clear?
我们就能离开这鬼地方 明白了吗？
Get 'em up, you French ponce.
举起手来，你个法国男妓
But, Mr English, I'm gobsmacked!
不过，英格力先生，我真得很吃惊！
What an unexpected surprise.
真是意想不到的吃惊！
Surprises are very much my speciality, Sauvage.
惊奇非常是我的专业，苏瓦吉
I think we've seen enough of this.
我想这我们已经看够了
I know exactly what you're planning, and I'm here to put a stop to it.
我很清楚地明白你们的计划，我来这就是为了阻止它
My bottom will be king of England before you are.
我的屁股也会在你之前成为英国国王的
Wrong again.
又错了
Perhaps you'd care to look behind you.
或许你介意看看你身后
Oh, please.
哦，请了
Lorna!
萝娜！
I'm sorry, Johnny.
对不起，强尼
Well, I'm afraid that we'll have to...
好吧，我很遗憾今晚我们不得不…
conclude the floor show for tonight.
结束夜总会的节目表演了
Not so fast, Sauvage.
没那么容易，苏瓦吉
You may have taken me, but you'll never take England.
你可以抓住我，但你永远控制不了英国
Not as long as I have breath in my body...
不只是我还能呼吸…
or a bullet in my gun.
还有我枪中有子弹
You know, Mr English, I'm going to miss you. Really.
你知道吗，英格力先生，我真的会想你的
You're very entertaining. I thank you.
你真得很搞笑，我谢谢你
Take them away.
带他们走
Good morning, everybody,
大家早上好啊
and welcome to the breakfast show.
欢迎收听早餐秀
As the crowds are gathering here for the crowning of our first French king...
人群在这儿集结就是为了我们首位法国国王的加冕…
since the year 1066,
自从1066年以来
call here at London FM with the top ten things you most love about the French.
这是伦敦调频，我们将通过热线电话述说我们最爱法国的10件事
We haven 't had any calls yet, uh, at all,
我们目前还没接到任何热线
but the lines are still open and I'll give you that number again...
但线路依然开通着，我将再播报一次热线号码…
Zero, deux, Zero, sept...
０－２－０－７…
This is not good, Johnny.
这不对，强尼
We've got to think of something.
我们该好好想想
Wait a minute. I've got an idea.
等等，我有主意了
Hop! Hop!
跳！ 跳！
And hop! And hop! And stop!
再跳！ 再跳！停！
Now, are you familiar...
现在，你对危地马拉三角洲的…
with the shaman throat warblers of the Guatemalan delta?
萨满教道士用喉咙发颤音熟悉吗？
What?
什么？
It has long been their belief...
他们很久以来信奉…
that a whistle pitched at the precise resonant frequency of a metal lock...
口哨的发音频率会引起金属锁的共鸣…
will vibrate the levers in such a way that the door will simply swing open.
共鸣所产生的震动将会使门很轻松的打开
Unbelievable.
难以置信
And kneel.
跪下
Right. Here goes.
好的 开始了
- I can't hear anything. - I'm into ultrasonic.
- 我听不到任何声音了 - 我在发出超声波
Will you just stop all this and face facts?
强尼，你能不那么干而面对现实吗？
We've failed. The only thing that can save us now is a miracle.
我们失败了 能救我们的唯一希望就是奇迹
It worked!
有效果了！
- Ohh! - Sir?
- 哦！ - 长官？
I don't know why you hauled yourself up that dreadful poo tube, Bough,
我不知道你为什么要从那该死的排粪管进来，大宝
when there was a perfectly good ladder right beside it.
在那旁边有个很棒的梯子
Now, Sauvage may have fooled the country...
现在，苏瓦吉可能已经愚弄了这个国家…
with his fake archbishop and his secret agenda,
靠他的假大主教，和他的秘密议程，
but he hasn't fooled me.
但他没法愚弄我
So, here's the plan.
那么，计划是这样的
Sirs, you are hereby called to witness the anointing...
阁下，你将神圣的被涂油证明为…
of your one true lord and future king Pascal.
一个真正的君主，未来的派斯卡国王
Pascal, are you willing to take the oath?
派斯卡，你愿意宣誓吗？
I am willing.
我愿意
Then be thou anointed...
那么你将被涂上…
with this holy oil.
这圣油
And do you, the chosen bishops of England, Scotland and Wales,
你所选定的，英格兰、苏格兰和威尔士的主教，
ascent to this anointing?
愿意涂上圣油吗？
For Scotland, I do.
为了苏格兰，我愿意
For Wales, I do.
为了威尔士，我愿意
For England, I do not!
为了英格兰，我不愿意！
English!?
英格力！
That man must not be crowned king because he is...
那家伙不能被加冕为国王，因为他是…
a fraudster, a charlatan and a thief.
一个骗子，一个吹牛者，还是一个贼
No, please. Let him speak.
没事，让他说下去
It is this man, Pascal Sauvage,
这家伙，派斯卡·苏瓦吉
who stole the Crown Jewels,
他偷了王室珠宝
who forced the queen to abdicate...
他强迫女王让位…
and who would kill anyone who got in his way.
他会杀死所有挡他路的人
It is the end, Herr English.
结束了，英格力先生
He has cheated, conned and manipulated...
他已经欺骗并操纵…
this great country for his own ends.
这伟大的国家为他自己的目的所用
He's fooled you all!
他愚弄了你们全部所有人！
What's more, this whole ceremony is a sham...
更有甚者，这整个典礼都是假的…
because that man standing in front of you...
因为那个站在你们面前的人…
is not the archbishop of Canterbury.
不是坎特伯雷大主教
English, a word of advice: Don't go there.
英格力，给你个忠告: 别到那儿去
Shut it, Frenchy. I'll go wherever I damn well please.
闭嘴，法国佬，我愿意到哪儿就去哪儿
- Now take it off. - What?
- 现在把面具摘下来 - 什么？
Your face is made of plastic.
你的面具是塑胶造的
Remove it at once.
立即摘掉
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我不明白你在说些什么
Right. I'll just have to remove it myself.
好吧 我自己动手摘掉它
Come on!
赶快啊！
Maybe it pulls up from the front.
或许要从前面来弄掉
Come on, you!
快啊！
- Aaah! - Thank you very much.
- 啊！ - 非常感谢
Must be a join here somewhere.
某处定有连接的地方
Fascinating performance as always, Monsieur English,
总是神神道道，英格力先生
but I'm afraid we must move on.
但我想我们必须继续
Nobody's moving anywhere until I'm finished with this piece of low- life.
没人可以离开，直到我最终揭穿这一切
Do you or do you you not...
你是否在你的…
have tattooed on your bottom the words,
屁股上纹有如下文字
"Jesus is coming... look busy?"
“天国已近，赶快加油？”
Are you insane?
你是不是有神经病啊？
Well, let's find out, shall we?
好吧，让我们找出来看看，好吗？
Go on, over. Let's have a look.
我们来看看
Excellent!
棒极了！
All right, so I was wrong about the archbishop's bottom.
好吧，对于大主教的屁股我是搞错了
- But there's more. - But not, I'm afraid, today.
- 但是还有 - 但是我恐怕今天没有了
Sergeant, please take this man away.
警卫，把这家伙带走
- But be gentle with him. - Do you think that's it?
- 但对他要斯文点 - 你认为就那样了吗？
You think I don't have more evidence?
你认为我就没有更多的证据了？
My loyal subordinate is standing by with a DVD...
我最忠诚的属下争看着部DVD…
which shows Sauvage's hideous plans forthis country.
那里面有苏瓦吉对这个国家的丑恶计划
Get him out! Get him out of here!
把他拖出去！把他拖出去！
- Play it, Bough! Play the disk! - Play it! Now!
- 方啊，大宝！ 快播放那光盘！ - 放啊！就现在！
∮ You're so hot teasing me ∮
∮ 你多么热辣戏弄我 ∮
∮ So you're blue, but I can't take a chance on a chick like you ∮
∮ 你正忧郁，但我不能趁机占你这样年轻女孩的便宜 ∮
∮ It's somethin' I couldn't do ∮
∮ 这是我不会做的事 ∮
∮ Well, I can dance with you, honey if you think it's funny ∮
∮ 噢，我可以和你跳舞，宝贝如果你觉得这样有趣的话 ∮
∮ Doesyour mother know that you're out ∮
∮ 你妈妈知道你出来了吗？ ∮
∮ And I could shout with you, baby Flirt a little, maybe ∮
∮ 我会对你叫嚣，宝贝，或许你可以风骚一些 ∮
∮ Doesyour mother know that you're out ∮
∮ 你妈妈知道你出来了吗？ ∮
∮ Take it easy ∮
∮ 不要紧张 ∮
∮ Better slow down, girl That's no way to go ∮
∮ 最好慢一些，女孩，你无路可走 ∮
∮ Doesyour mother know ∮
∮ 你妈妈知道你出来了吗？ ∮
- Oi! - Hey!
- 诶！ - 嘿！
Well, shall we?
那么，我们继续吧？
Then as Solomon was anointed king...
那么正如所罗门王…
by Zadok the priest and Nathan the prophet,
让匝多克牧师和内森先知涂圣油为王
so be thou anointed...
所以你被涂以圣油…
and consecrated king...
尊崇为王…
over all the peoples... whom the Lord thy God...
统治所有上帝…
hath given thee to govern...
所分派与你的…
and of all your possessions,
人民…
wherever they may be.
及他们所在的
And so, in the name of the Father...
那么，以天父之名…
and of the Son...
以圣子之名…
and of the Holy Ghost,
及圣灵之名
I crown you
我为您加冕…
Damn it!
见鬼！
- Give it back! - No!
- 还给我！ - 不！
- That is my crown! - Never!
- 那是我的王冠！ - 决不给你！
- Give it back! - Never in a million years, Sauvage!
- 还给我！ - 数百万年都绝不给你，苏瓦吉！
- Give it to me! - Get off.
- 给我！ - 下来
Merde!
见鬼！
Give it back!
还给我！
- Stop! - Shut up!
- 停！ - 闭嘴！
All this stupid little country have to do is stand in line...
所有这些小国家要做的就是站成一条线…
and do what it's told for one miserable day!
干那些受难日该干的事！
But can it do that?
但做不到呢？
My fragrant French ass, it can!
我的法国香屁股可以！
Merde!
见鬼！
Aah!
啊！
Give it! The crown, eh? The crown! Go!
给我加冕！快加冕！
And so, in the name of the Father...
那么，以天父之名…
and of the Son and of the Holy Ghost,
以圣子之名，还有圣灵之名，
I crown you...
我加冕您为…
king.
国王
What
什么…
Arrest that man...
逮捕那家伙…
and lock him away.
把他锁起来抓走
Words can hardly expressjust how much we appreciate everything you've done.
言语已不能表达我们对你们所做一切的由衷敬意
Nothing more than my duty, ma'am.
那都是我应该做的，夫人
And in return, is there anything that your queen and country can do for you?
作为回报，你的女王跟国家能为你做些什么呢？
Well,
嗯
since one is asking, ma'am
因为有人要求，夫人…
In celebration of her return to the throne,
在庆祝回归王位的庆典上，
the queen has declaredAugust 5 a national holiday...
女王宣布8月5日为国定假日…
and has conferred a knighthood on the unnamed MI7 agent...
并授予无名的军情七处探员骑士身份…
responsible for foiling the plot of French businessman Pascal Sauvage.
以表彰他粉碎法国商人派斯卡·苏瓦吉的阴谋
Mr Sauvage is now awaiting trial for high treason,
苏瓦吉正等待着以叛国罪的审判
a crime which still carries the death penalty.
这是会处以极刑的罪名
If found guilty, he's asked that his brain be donated to medical science...
如果发现有罪，他会被要求捐赠大脑来做医学研究…
to further research into the causes ofhyper manic schizophrenia.
来进一步探究狂躁精神病
Meanwhile, the unnamed English agent has left the country...
期间，无名的英格力探员已经离开了这国家…
and has already embarked on his next challenging mission.
踏上了他下一个新的任务的征途
（法国南部某处）
Sir Johnny English.
强尼·英格力长官
Her Majesty did seem very grateful.
女王看起来很感激的样子
She's not the only one.
她不是唯一
Mmm. You are full of surprises.
嗯 你充满惊奇
Aaaah!
啊！
- Johnny! - Oh, f...
- 强尼！ - 哦…
（功臣英格力授勋为爵士）